Once there was a little boy who wanted to die…
Boy Interrupted is a documentary film directed by Dana Heinz Perry.
On the night of Oct.
2, 2005, Hart and Dana Perry's 15-year-old son Evan jumped to
his death from his New York City bedroom window.
This moving film is the story, told by his filmmaker parents and others who knew him, of
Evan’s life and death, and his life-long struggle with bipolar disorder.
It delves into the complexity of Evan's disease, sharing his
family's journey through the maze of mental illness.
In showing how one family deals with generations of loss and grief, the film defies the stigma
related to mental illness and suicide and tells a human story that touches everyone.
Himself, played by Evan Scott Perry.
Self - Evan's Mother, played by Dana Heinz Perry.
Self - Evan's Father, played by Hart Perry.
Self - Evan's Half-Brother, played by Nicholas Kopple-Perry.
Self - Teacher, played by Karen Riposo.
Self - Doctor, played by Ladd Spiegel.
Boy Interrupted is a 2009 documentary film  on the life and death of Evan
Perry, who experienced bipolar depression from a young age.
When  his parents, Dana and Hart Perry, consulted  psychiatrists about Evan's suicidal comments or other signs of depression, medical professionals did not
believe that he was mentally ill, and the footage was originally intended to show his symptoms and  help  access to the treatment he needed.
Evan was diagnosed with depression at age 5, and was
later diagnosed with bipolar depression.
Despite the treatment and medication received, he
died by suicide in 2005 at age 15.
Evan Perry had a family medical history involving serious mental illnesses.
The documentary  focuses on how his bipolar depression
affected him and those close to him.
About four years after Evan's death, the documentary was shown at the
Sundance Film Festival and released on television and DVD.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.